<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">

  <p> A use case scenarios for FHIR-based Terminology Change Set Exchange is described below and illustrated in a sequence diagram. 

</p>
<a name="changesetusecase"></a>
  <h3>Terminology Change Set Exchange Use Case</h3>
<p>
In this example, a terminology publishing organization is making an incremental change to its extension of SNOMED CT by adding a new concept. To enable data exchange with a close trading partner that makes use of this extended concept, this publishing organization shares a Terminology Change Set with a the trading partner (the Terminology Consumer identified in the steps below).
</p>
<ol>
	<li>
	<b>Authoring Environment:</b> Terminologist creates a new concept to extend SNOMED CT, exports it as a Terminology Change Set, and posts it to the FHIR server
	</li>
	<li>
	<b>Terminology Consumer:</b> Requests the Terminology Change Set from the FHIR server
	</li>
	<li>
	<b>FHIR Server:</b> Delivers the FHIR Resource Bundle requested
	</li>
	<li>
	<b>Terminology Consumer:</b> Updates the Local Terminology Database with the contents of the Terminology Change Set retrieved
	</li>
</ol>
<img src="ChangeSetInteractionDiagram.png" width="80%" alt="Change Set Interaction Diagram"/>
<a name="changesetusecase1"></a>
<h3> Scenario 1: Change Set of SNOMED CT Data</h3>
<p> 
<b>Key Objective </b>: Modifying existing SNOMED CT concepts, including changes to their defining semantics, can be exported from one source and imported to another system.
</p>
<ol> 
	<li> 
	<b>Precondition:</b>
	</li>
	<li>
	Users have access to an integrated knowledge representation (IKM) platform to view and edit SNOMED CT data
	</li>
	<li>
	SNOMED CT release files have been installed.
	</li>
	<li>
	The system supports FHIR generation and/or ingest capability based on the SNOMED Change Set CodeSystem profile.
	</li>
	<li>
	<b>Step 1 - Modify the semantics for existing SNOMED CT concepts.</b>
	</li>
	<li>
	<b> Actions:</b>
	</li>
	<li>	
	1. Search/navigate for SNOMED CT Concepts. 
	</li>
	2. Edit SNOMED CT concepts
	</li>
	<li>
	<b>Step 2 - Post change set to FHIR server</b>
	</li>
	<li>
	<b> Actions:</b>
	</li>
	<li>	
	1. Export and post the change set including underlying smenaitcs as CodeSystem and Provenance resources on a FHIR server
	</li>
	<li>
	<b>Step 3 - Consuming system retrieves and ingests change set from FHIR server</b>
	</li>
	<li>
	<b> Actions:</b>
	</li>
	<li>	
	1. Retrieve CodeSystem and Provenance resources from FHIR server
	</li>
	2. Ingest to local terminology representation complete change set inclding underlying
	</li>
	<li>
	<b>Scenario Success Criteria:</b>
	</li>
	<li>	
	Consuming system can ingest change set without error
	</li>
	<li>
	Post-ingestion, changes included in change set are visible within the consuming system
	</li>
	</div>