<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <!-- The spaces between the open and close "a" tag are mandatory.  (Cuz HTML renderers are dumb...) -->
  <a name="intro"> </a>
  <h3>Introduction</h3>
	<p>
The Tinkar Reference Model is a logical model that describes the standardized model for terminology and change
management, previously published in the <a href="">HL7 Logical Model: Standardized Terminology Knowledgebase, Release 1</a>. 
Tinkar provides an architecture that delivers integrated terminology to the enterprise and its information
systems. 

It was designed to support the healthcare enterprise need for an extensive terminology foundation and the ability
to implement extensions to support diverse informatics systems. It supports standard terminology modules, value sets, and coding systems as well as local
terms and equivalence mappings.

In this edition, standardized data exchange formats and transactions are defined to specifically enable the exchange Tinkar-compliant Terminology change sets, both in a lossless Protobuf format, as well as utilizing FHIR CodeSystem and Provenance resources.
  </p>
	<a name="technical"> </a>
	<h3>Technical Overview</h3>
	<p>
    Additional detail/context setting for those who have significant background in the domain.  (Try to make as understandable as you can, but
    set important context).
  </p>
  <a name="walkthrough"> </a>
  <p>
    The main sections of this IG are:
  </p>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="background.html">Background</a> - provides business context for the implementation guide and information that implementers should be
      familiar with before reading the remainder of the IG.  There could be multiple pages for this.
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="spec.html">Detailed Specification</a> - The actual stuff implementers are expected to do.  (Could be multiple pages for this.)
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="downloads.html">Downloads</a> - Allows downloading a copy of this implementation guide and other useful information
    </li>
  </ul>
</div>
