<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <!-- The spaces between the open and close "a" tag are mandatory.  (Cuz HTML renderers are dumb...) -->
  <div style="width: 100%;" >
<h3 id="plain-language-summary-about-hl7-and-this-guide">Plain Language Summary about HL7 and this Guide<a class="anchorjs-link " href="#plain-language-summary-about-hl7-and-this-guide" aria-label="Anchor" data-anchorjs-icon="" style="font: 1em / 1 anchorjs-icons; padding-left: 0.375em;"></a>
  <button class="btn btn-info btn-lg collapsed" type="button" title="Click to Open or Close the Plain Language Summary" data-toggle="collapse" data-target="#plain-lang-summary" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapseExample">
    Welcome! Thank-you for wanting to learn about this guide.  Click Here to see the Plain Language Summary
  </button>
</h3>
</div>
<div class="collapse" id="plain-lang-summary" aria-expanded="false" style="height: 0px;">
  <div class="card card-body" style="border:1px solid;border-color:#cccccc;padding:10px">
<h4 id="about-this-guide">About this Guide<a class="anchorjs-link " href="#about-this-guide" aria-label="Anchor" data-anchorjs-icon="" style="font: 1em / 1 anchorjs-icons; padding-left: 0.375em;"></a></h4>

<p>The HL7 Terminology Change Set Implementation Guide offers a <strong> standardized </strong>, FHIR-based method for distributing medical terminology content, ensuring that all properties associated with each concept in the original terminology are included. This guide is primarily designed for healthcare IT professionals, developers, and organizations involved in creating or maintaining medical terminologies within their systems.</p>

<p>By adopting this guide, organizations can <strong> streamline their data ingestion processes </strong> for medical terminology content, leveraging a common FHIR representation. The guide provides detailed, step-by-step instructions and illustrative examples to assist users in effectively implementing terminology changes using HL7 standards.</p>

<p> Maintaining current medical terminology is essential for accurate data exchange, ensuring patient safety, and facilitating effective healthcare delivery. This guide supports these critical goals by providing a clear and consistent approach to managing and distributing terminology updates.</p>

  </div>
</div>
  <a name="intro"> </a>
  <h3>Introduction</h3>
	<p>
Custodians of standardized terminologies have developed rich semantic frameworks that can be used to interact with individual concepts in an elegant fashion, utilizing the relationships between terms to dynamically adjust user interfaces or derive clinical patterns. Today, these frameworks are distributed via proprietary formats and are tailored to the specific source terminology. As a result, any system looking to utilize the full semantic power of the terminology must build customized data pipelines to process those formats. This creates a significant implementer burden, as they must maintain different formats and data pipelines for each source terminolgoy they wish to use. Furthermore, not all terminologies define a standard format for distributing incremental changes, adding to the complexity of keeping systems up-to-date. 
</p>
<p>
This Implementation Guide (IG) provides profiles and implementation guidance on utilizing the CodeSystem resource for exchanging terminology change sets that include full semantic detail from the source terminology. A CodeSystem change set is a collection of concepts intended to be added to an existing published version as a temporary solution until the code system publisher provides an official update. Change sets should be a distribution format used for a specific version of a specific terminology, and not used to support operational transactions on a Terminology Server. It's important to note that Terminology Change Sets are designed to facilitate receiving systems in processing changes to CodeSystem.concept values. Therefore, they would be inappropriate to use with the CodeSystems whose concepts cannot be enumerated, such as UCUM. 
</p>
<p> Specifically, this IG enables a standardized distribution mechanism for terminology changes, reducing the implementer burden associated with managing diverse terminology ingestion pipelines from disparate sources by offering a reusable ingestion format. It also provides a consistent format for distributing incremental terminology changes, particularly beneficial for terminologies that currently lack such a standardized approach.  The expected result of ingesting a change set is that the Terminology Server should be prepared to make content from the new version of the terminology available. This IG also addresses exchanging terminology change sets containing concepts not yet incorporated into published source terminology versions, such as those requiring rapid distribution during a pandemic-response context. Analysis of semantic detail to include in a change set is informed by the <a href="TinkarOverview.html">Tinkar Standardized Terminology Knowledgebase Reference Model</a>, and mappings from that architecture are included on CodeSystem profiles.
  </p>
	<a name="technical"> </a>
	<h3>Technical Overview</h3>
	<p>
The design for Terminology Change Sets is primarily a robust utilization of the CodeSystem resource's modelling for <code>CodeSystem.concept</code> and <code>CodeSystem.property</code> to convey not just the concept identifiers and descriptions, but the full semantic design for each concept.  Additionally, a Provenance instance is used to provide insight into the creation of the Terminology Change Set, particularly using <code>Provenance.what</code> to reference the baseline Terminology from which the change set was derived.
  </p>
  <img src="TermChangeSetDesign.png" alt="Terminology Change Set Design"/>
  <a name="walkthrough"> </a>
  <p>
    The main sections of this IG are:
  </p>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="guidance.html">Guidance</a> - this page provides best practices and considerations for implementation of Terminology Change Sets.
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="TerminologyDistribution.html">Background</a> - these pages provide background on how incremental releases of Terminologies are currently handled, the need for a standardized Terminology Change Set format in FHIR, and an inventory of known FHIR limitations related to the inclusion of full semantic detail for terminology concepts.
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="artifacts.html">FHIR Artifacts</a> - this page provides the central source for all Profiles, Extensions, ValueSets, and Examples used in this IG.
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="TinkarBackground.html">Tinkar Reference Model</a> - these pages provide context and background for the Tinkar Reference Model, which informed the analysis and design for Terminology Change Set profiles.
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="downloads.html">Downloads</a> - this page provides links to downloadable artifacts.
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="changes.html">Change Log</a> - this page documents the changes across the versions of the Terminology Change Set IG.
    </li>
  </ul>
  	<a name="credits"> </a>
	<h3>Credits</h3>
<p>
This implementation guide was made possible by the thoughtful contributions of the following people and organizations:
<ul>
	<li>
	Keith Campbell MD PhD, US Food and Drug Administration (FDA)
	</li>
	<li>
	Marti Velezis, Sonrisa Consulting
	</li>
	<li>
	Russell Ott, Deloitte Consulting LLP
	</li>
	<li>
	Samuel Wescott, Deloitte Consulting LLP
	</li>
	<li>
	Matthew Deitz, Deloitte Consulting LLP
	</li>
	<li>
	Bimla Siwakoti, Deloitte Consulting LLP
	</li>
	<li>
	Jess Bota, Apelon
	</li>
	<li>
	Andrea Pitkus PhD MLS(ASCP)<sup>CM</sup> FAMIA, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health
	</li>
	<li>
	Carol Macumber, Clinical Architecture
	</li>
</ul>
</p>
	<a name="crossversion"></a>
	<h3>Cross Version Analysis</h3>
{% include cross-version-analysis.xhtml %}
	<a name="dependency"></a>
	<h3>Dependency Table</h3>
{% include dependency-table.xhtml %}
	<a name="globals"></a>
	<h3>Globals Statements</h3>
{% include globals-table.xhtml %}
	<a name="ip"></a>
	<h3>IP Statements</h3>
{% include ip-statements.xhtml %}
</div>
