<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
    <a name="what"> </a>
    <h3> What is Protobuf? </h3>
    <p> 
    Protocol Buffers (Protobuf) stands as a robust and efficient data serialization framework 
    crafted by Google. Protocol Buffers Documentation (
    <a href="https://protobuf.dev/">https://protobuf.dev/</a>). At its core, 
    Protobuf aims to provide language-agnostic and platform-agnostic means of encoding structured data. 
    This is achieved through the definition of data structures using a straightforward and human-readable 
    schema language. The resulting serialization process produces compact binary data, facilitating 
    seamless transmission between diverse systems and programming languages. One of Protobuf's key 
    strengths lies in its extensibility, allowing developers to modify data structures over time while 
    maintaining backward compatibility. The framework's efficiency, both in terms of space utilization 
    and processing speed, coupled with its support for multiple programming languages, positions Protobuf 
    as a compelling solution for applications where rapid and interoperable data exchange is a critical 
    consideration. Further insights into Protobuf's features, applications, and advantages can be explored 
    in the official documentation, accessible at (<a href="https://protobuf.dev/overview/">
    https://protobuf.dev/overview/</a>). 
    </p>
    <a name="why"> </a>
    <h3>Why Protobuf?</h3>
    <p> 
    <b>Gaps in FHIR Representation for Tinkar Serialization Data:</b> 
    The need for an effective serialization mechanism for Tinkar data arose due to limitations in the 
    FHIR representation. Recognizing these gaps, alternative solutions were explored to enhance 
    serialization efficiency and overcome specific challenges. 
    </p>
    <p> 
    <b>Exploring Options:</b> 
    In response to the gaps identified in FHIR representation, a search for suitable solutions led to 
    the evaluation of various options. The goal was to find a serialization method that could effectively 
    address the shortcomings and seamlessly integrate with Tinkar serialization data. 
    </p>
 
</div>

