<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
	<h3>About Tinkar</h3>
<p>
Tinkar provides the foundation of a knowledge architecture that is intended to integrate reference terminology from distributors (e.g., SNOMED CT®, LOINC®, RxNorm) 
with local concepts to support interoperable information semantics across the enterprise. 
</p>
<p>
This specification introduces an agile approach to terminology design and formatting that promotes the use of self- describing data. It is a shift from hard-coded 
models that have been favored due to their prescriptive nature but have shown limited flexibility and extensibility. Like FHIR, this specification places the focus 
on a self-describing, extensible approach to representing terminology. Therefore, Tinkar aims to be both self-describing and completely machine processed: 
</p>
<ol>
	<li>
	Self-describing machine-readable representation of terminology, such that if an application can process the metadata, it should be able to import the content/concepts 
	and make it available to enterprise applications. 
	</li>
	<li>
	The machine-readable terminology could generate human-readable documentation so that business analysts and developers can understand and apply it correctly.
	</li>
</ol>
<h3>Tinkar Objectives and Purpose - Manage Terminology and Change</h3>
<p>
This specification describes the requirements and characteristics of systems required to manage terminology produced by a variety of organizations across a healthcare enterprise. 
This foundation must allow enterprise to extend terminology standards and implement extensions in a timely fashion.
</p>
<p>
This specification is intended to support healthcare organizations' standard terminology modules, value sets, and coding systems as well as local terms and equivalence mappings. 
</p>
<p>
A standard-based Tinkar specification is necessary to support the operation of a variety of systems intended to deliver knowledge management for terminology to vendors, 
providers, and even standards-development organizations, like HL7. 
</p>
<h3>Related Efforts</h3>



</div>
